# NIHAL

### BUSINESS OPERATIONS ASSOCIATE

#### **CONTACT INFORMATION**



nihaldino1997@gmail.com



+91 9791268607



www.linkedin.com/in/nihal07



Chennai, India

#### **EDUCATION**

- B.E Mechanical (2014 2018)
   Chennai institute of technology, Chennai
   CGPA 7.6
- HSC (2013 2014)
   Our Lady Matric Hr sec school, Chennai
   Percentage 76.8
- SSLC (2011 2012)
   Madha Matric Hr sec school, Chennai
   Percentage 84

#### **SKILLS**

Microsoft Office Suite
Data analysis and visualization

- Excel
- Tableau

Data Manipulation and Analysis

- SQL
- Numpy
- Pandas

Programming Language

Python

**S4 HANA** 

Laptop SKU creation
SOP Creation

**OEE** and **OLE** calculation

#### **INTERNSHIP**

- · CATERPILLAR INDIA PVT LTD, Tiruvallur
- ROYAL Enfield, Oragadam, Chennai

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Business Operations Associate in Product Data Management at HP Inc with 4 years of experience in Supply Chain Management, identifying and coordinating process improvement initiatives that incorporate best practices and standard operating procedures. Identifies and implement prioritized projects for organizational transformation. S4 HANA, Python, SQL , Tableau Proficiency and demonstrated skill managing and driving multiple projects with minimal supervision.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## HP Computing and Printing Systems India, Chennai Business Operations Associate - JAN 2021 – Present

- Worldwide production and delivery of Personal systems group (PSG) products like Notebooks, Desktops and workstations in Product data management using SAM-T, MS4, S4 HANA, SAP.
- Releasing the document of Bill of Material (BOM)as a Stock Keeping Unit (SKU).
- Perform all daily/weekly/monthly processes diligently without any backlog thereby meet key deliverables.
- Participate with weekly issue log meeting with SME.
- Work closely with Purchasing to review the supportability of overdue parts from suppliers.

#### WHEELS INDIA PVT LTD, Chennai

Graduate Engineering Trainee - JAN 2020 - APRIL 2020

 End to end coordination from "Purchase to Pay" of Energy Equipments like Wind Turbines and machined components for various other applications. Inventory Management.

## ASCO NUMATICS INDIA PVT LTD. EMERSON, Chennai Graduate Apprentice Trainee - JAN 2019 – JAN 2020

- SOP creation For Fluid Control and Pneumatic Products.
- PO creation for Line management.
- 5S Implementations in Shop Floor.
- · OEE and OLE Calculation.